



### Product Designer

- (a) (669)-246-2810
- jessie\_lyu@berkeley.edu
- jessielyu.me

I'm a motivated product designer with strength in UX Research, UX Design, and software engineering.

I designed for creativity and love, aimed at bringing innovation and joy from ordinary. Currently I' pursuing my master's degreen of Information Management and Systems in University of California, Berkeley.

#### Skillset

- Sketch
- Figma
- Adobe Suites
  Qualitative research
  - Software prototype
  - Frontend development

## Experience

### University of California, Berkeley

Graduate Student Instructor August, 2018 - December, 2018

• Teach "User Interface Design" class as a graduate student instructor, comprehensively instruct on students on user research processes, HCI concepts, human-centered design principles and Android mobile app development.

#### Yahoo!, Inc.

Software Engineer Jun, 2016 - July, 2018

- · Worked in Yahoo Global Search team, implemented and launched Search Middleware platform which has millions of users each day on mobile/PC devices
- Designed and developed an internal Search System debugging tool, significantly descreased trouble shooting time for engineers and editors by at least 1/3
- Worked as both designer and engineer to develop a Search UI configuration tool using React.js

#### Quicket Solutions, Inc.

Software Engineer Sep, 2015 - May 2016

- Helped research, design, and implement UI of software for cloud based e-ticket system to help police officers more efficiently track tickets, warnings, and driver information
- Worked on product iterations, conducted contextual inquiries and usability tests
- Launched the application in many cities, named a finalist in Amazon's City on a Cloud Innovation Challenge 2015

### Education (



### University of California, Berkeley Master of Information Management and Systems

Focus: Product Design | UX Design

Anticipated: 2020

### University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign

B.S. Computer Engineering, with Honors Minor Mathematics 2016

# Projects (



### TechExchange - Website Redesign

**UX** Designer

October, 2018

Redesign the visual and layout for TechExchange's website (techexchange.org), which is a nonprofit organization aims at bringing technoligy to low-income households.

### Dalian - IOS APP

Product Designer

June, 2017 - August, 2017

Dalian is an IOS application aimed at creating a new experience for users to digest news and information, featuring user-generated content.